<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mtb on bigelectrons</title><link>https://www.bigelectrons.com/tags/mtb/</link><description>Recent content in mtb on bigelectrons</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2018 - 2022 @ https://github.com/Joesan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bigelectrons.com/tags/mtb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Trek Remedy clocks 1000 km this season</title><link>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-trek-remedy-1000-km/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-trek-remedy-1000-km/</guid><description>
So as of today, I managed to clock on record a total of 1000 Km with my Trek Remedy 8. It is obviously much higher than that as for several rides I haven't turned my Sigma odometer device. But for the record, the mileage is 1000 Km for this year so far.
Image not found a.warning-link { color: inherit !important; font-weight: inherit !important; text-decoration: underline !important; border-bottom: none !</description></item><item><title>Send it... yep! Sendin it...</title><link>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ramp-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ramp-1/</guid><description>
What does &amp;quot;Send it mean? It's a jargon used within the Mountain Biking community, especially the Downhill community that indicates that you are about to hit a jump and that you have to clear the jump! Jumpin on the trails requires technique, a lot of practice. One way to practice the technique is to do it using some artificially made ramps! That exactly was my DIY project this weekend! I went to the local store &amp;quot;Bauhaus&amp;quot; as it is called here in Germany and shopped for some wood and nails.</description></item><item><title>How is it to experience a Blackout</title><link>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-black-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-black-out/</guid><description>
Today, I drove to Düsseldorf to Mountain bike the Aaper wald. I made a nasty mistake of not having enough breakfast. It started good, but after reaching the foot of the hill, I started to ride the up-hill section. After pedalling for about a minute or two, I started to notice that my legs were pounding hard. I feel that this must be the activity of my heart trying to pump more blood to my legs to feed them with power.</description></item><item><title>Back with MTB Tours and Downhill rides</title><link>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-1/</guid><description>
Mountain biking is addictive! Worse than drugs!
After a couple of months of staying away from my MTB, I'm back with it and I'm looking forward to this season to ride as much as possible and more importantly, without any accidents and injuries! I got my bike serviced and about a week ago. This is how &amp;quot;The Beast&amp;quot; looked after returning back from the service!
Image not found a.</description></item></channel></rss>