<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Miscellaneous on bigelectrons</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/categories/miscellaneous/</link><description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on bigelectrons</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2018 - 2025 @ https://github.com/Joesan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bigelectrons.com/categories/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A DIY Forearm Trainer Kit</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/diy-forearm-trainer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/diy-forearm-trainer/</guid><description>
I occasionally get physically active and do some training. I was figuring out what kind of physical activity that I could do when I'm sitting. This is when I thought about doing some exercises for the forearm.
As I'm someone who loves to DIY, I wanted to figure out which actions I want my forearm to do, and I remember being a teenager doing some dumbbell training that had to be rolled with both your arms stretched out.</description></item><item><title>Navigating the Pentatonic Scale in Triangles</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-navigating-pentatonic-scale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-navigating-pentatonic-scale/</guid><description>
Climbing the Pentatonic scales Recently, I can say that I made very good progress playing across the neck of my guitar. I memorized few pentatonic shapes, but I was stuck the whole while on those specific boxes. The whole thing did not make any sense to me. Just wandering within those boxes is not pleasant music. Frustrated, I looked at Youtube for some motivational ideas on how to unstuck me from the boxes.</description></item><item><title>Red Wing 3140 Work Chukka</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/red-wing-3140/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/red-wing-3140/</guid><description>
Disclaimer: I'm not paid to write about this post, this is purely my ownership experience using these boots!
A blog on a pair of shoes? A bit unusual for my blog that I'm writing about a pair of shoes. It is still just a shoe, but it is a Red Wing Chukka, the 3140 in the Oro-Iginal leather. There is a reason why I'm writing about this piece of hardware that brings joy and comfort to my knee and foot.</description></item><item><title>Moved from Blogger to GH Pages</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/blogger-to-gh-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/blogger-to-gh-pages/</guid><description>
I have been documenting so far with Blogger. Recently I started to do some Robotics projects with ROS. As I was doing it, I was looking for ways to get all what I do be documented. I know Github offers GH Pages, but I was a bit reluctant to try it out. So for the Navo project, I decided that GH Pages will be the source for my documentation, hence I wanted to give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Once more a blow, a nasty one this time</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-6/</guid><description>
I could not say this more than what the title says. I had a very severe blow to my already damaged left knee. First a bit of history here and here.
It was on the 28th of September where I went for my first ever defensive sport training called &amp;quot;VingTsun&amp;quot;. Inspired by my Physio friend who is a beginner, I decided to give this training a try. I indeed watched few videos of it before committing myself to joining him for the training session which starts around 20:00 Hours near to where I live.</description></item><item><title>On Navigating the Pentatonic scale</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-2/</guid><description>
Recently, I can say that I made very good progress playing across the neck of my guitar. I memorized few pentatonic shapes, but I was stuck the whole while on those specific boxes. The whole thing did not make any sense to me. Just wandering within those boxes is not pleasant music. Frustrated, I looked at Youtube for some motivational ideas on how to unstuck me from the boxes.
Luckily, this one video in Youtube that I found on a random search helped me immensely.</description></item><item><title>My journey thus far with learning to play the guitar</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-1/</guid><description>
I remember my interest to play the guitar started in the year 2012 and without any hesitation, I went and purchased my first ever electric guitar, the Ibanez GSA 60 and a small Marshall amplifier. I'm not sure at that point in time if it was the right decision to start with an electric guitar but as I recollect, I don't think I made any significant progress with it. I was even struggling to play the basic chord shapes.</description></item><item><title>Oh my left knee - You cause my problems!</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-5/</guid><description>
This morning it was just a normal day as always. We always have some balloons in our hall as my younger daughter likes to play it like a volleyball with me. I also enjoy entertaining her for some time.
So there were a few balloons in the hall, which I casually like to kick. As I kicked one with my right leg, my left leg kind of went out of balance, it twisted (as I have no cross ligaments because of my MTB accident 2 years ago.</description></item><item><title>My Trek Remedy clocks 1000 km this season</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-trek-remedy-1000-km/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-trek-remedy-1000-km/</guid><description>
So as of today, I managed to clock on record a total of 1000 Km with my Trek Remedy 8. It is obviously much higher than that as for several rides I haven't turned my Sigma odometer device. But for the record, the mileage is 1000 Km for this year so far.
I have explored much of the singles trails around my area! It was fun riding this bike! I hope to do even more miles for the next season!</description></item><item><title>Yet another impact on the injured knee!</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-4/</guid><description>
Last Thursday, I took a day off. As the weather was good I decided to take my kids and my mom to Apeldoorn in the Netherlands. We wanted to visit the theme park and spend the day there. My mom is here with us in Germany to visit us and to take care of the kids during their summer vacation. Apeldoorn is a 2-hour drive from where we live. As usual, we did not manage to start early and ended up reaching our destination around 12:00.</description></item><item><title>Send it... yep! Sendin it...</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ramp-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ramp-1/</guid><description>
What does &amp;quot;Send it mean? It's a jargon used within the Mountain Biking community, especially the Downhill community that indicates that you are about to hit a jump and that you have to clear the jump! Jumpin on the trails requires technique, a lot of practice. One way to practice the technique is to do it using some artificially made ramps! That exactly was my DIY project this weekend! I went to the local store &amp;quot;Bauhaus&amp;quot; as it is called here in Germany and shopped for some wood and nails.</description></item><item><title>How is it to experience a Blackout</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-black-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-black-out/</guid><description>
Today, I drove to Düsseldorf to Mountain bike the Aaper wald. I made a nasty mistake of not having enough breakfast. It started good, but after reaching the foot of the hill, I started to ride the up-hill section. After pedalling for about a minute or two, I started to notice that my legs were pounding hard. I feel that this must be the activity of my heart trying to pump more blood to my legs to feed them with power.</description></item><item><title>Back with MTB Tours and Downhill rides</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/mtb-ride-1/</guid><description>
Mountain biking is addictive! Worse than drugs!
After a couple of months of staying away from my MTB, I'm back with it and I'm looking forward to this season to ride as much as possible and more importantly, without any accidents and injuries! I got my bike serviced and about a week ago. This is how &amp;quot;The Beast&amp;quot; looked after returning back from the service!
I took it for a spin in the trails around Düsseldorf.</description></item><item><title>4 Months update of my Knee</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-3/</guid><description>
It is now roughly 4 months since I injured my knee and the recovery so far has been very positive. On the downside, I have the feeling that my knee is not like it was before! Occasionally I get a strange wobbly feeling on my injured knee!
So for the first 2 months, I was not able to fully stretch or bend my injured leg, but that got a lot better now.</description></item><item><title>The beauty that goes behind a Mechanical watch</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/nomos-tangente-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/nomos-tangente-1/</guid><description>
Mechanical watches - They are the representation of artistic ingenuity. If you are wondering what is so fascinating about mechanical watches, I welcome you to take a look at some Youtube videos that shows how a mechanical watch is manufactured. It is after knowing, understanding and appreciating the artwork that goes behind the making of a mechanical watch, I decided that I will get one for myself.
I'm not a watch collector, I have never owned a time piece until I got my first mechanical watch in the spring of 2018.</description></item><item><title>6 Weeks Update of my Knee</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-2/</guid><description>
Roughly 3 weeks ago on the 5th of October, I had an MTB bike accident and in the process I ended up injuring my left knee. I was actually attempting to Manual during which I realized that I was about to lose my balance. I wanted to bail out from the Manual, so I tried to pull the bike completely to the front with me jump landing behind the rear wheels, but the bailout got totally out of control and eventually I ended up twisting my left knee soon after the jump.</description></item><item><title>What it is like to twist your knee?</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/acl-knee-injury-1/</guid><description>
Roughly 3 weeks ago on the 5th of October, I had an MTB bike accident and in the process I ended up injuring my left knee. I was actually attempting to Manual during which I realized that I was about to lose my balance. I wanted to bail out from the Manual, so I tried to pull the bike completely to the front with me jump landing behind the rear wheels, but the bailout got totally out of control and eventually I ended up twisting my left knee soon after the jump.</description></item></channel></rss>