<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guitar on bigelectrons</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/tags/guitar/</link><description>Recent content in Guitar on bigelectrons</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2018 - 2022 @ https://github.com/Joesan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bigelectrons.com/tags/guitar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating the Pentatonic Scale in Triangles</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-navigating-pentatonic-scale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-navigating-pentatonic-scale/</guid><description>
Climbing the Pentatonic scales Recently, I can say that I made very good progress playing across the neck of my guitar. I memorized few pentatonic shapes, but I was stuck the whole while on those specific boxes. The whole thing did not make any sense to me. Just wandering within those boxes is not pleasant music. Frustrated, I looked at Youtube for some motivational ideas on how to unstuck me from the boxes.</description></item><item><title>On Navigating the Pentatonic scale</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-2/</guid><description>
Recently, I can say that I made very good progress playing across the neck of my guitar. I memorized few pentatonic shapes, but I was stuck the whole while on those specific boxes. The whole thing did not make any sense to me. Just wandering within those boxes is not pleasant music. Frustrated, I looked at Youtube for some motivational ideas on how to unstuck me from the boxes.
Luckily, this one video in Youtube that I found on a random search helped me immensely.</description></item><item><title>My journey thus far with learning to play the guitar</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/misc/guitar-learning-1/</guid><description>
I remember my interest to play the guitar started in the year 2012 and without any hesitation, I went and purchased my first ever electric guitar, the Ibanez GSA 60 and a small Marshall amplifier. I'm not sure at that point in time if it was the right decision to start with an electric guitar but as I recollect, I don't think I made any significant progress with it. I was even struggling to play the basic chord shapes.</description></item></channel></rss>