<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technical Stuff on bigelectrons</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/categories/technical-stuff/</link><description>Recent content in Technical Stuff on bigelectrons</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2018 - 2022 @ https://github.com/Joesan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bigelectrons.com/categories/technical-stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handling Missing Data in Data Pre-Processing</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/handling-missing-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/handling-missing-data/</guid><description>
Handling missing data is a crucial step in the data preprocessing pipeline for any machine learning project. Imputation, the process of replacing missing data with substituted values, is essential for building robust and reliable models. This article explores various imputation techniques, provides code examples, and discusses the pros and cons of each method.
Understanding Missing Data Before diving into imputation techniques, it's important to understand the types of missing data:</description></item><item><title>Understanding Data Leakage in the ML Paradigm</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/data-leakage-in-ml/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/data-leakage-in-ml/</guid><description>
Data leakage is a critical issue in machine learning that can lead to overly optimistic performance metrics and poor generalization to new data. This article explains what data leakage is, why it is problematic, and how to avoid it during data pre-processing.
What is Data Leakage? Data leakage occurs when information from outside the training dataset is used to create the model. This means that the model inadvertently has access to information that it wouldn't normally have in a real-world scenario.</description></item><item><title>When a Bloom filter really blooms....</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/bloom-filter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/bloom-filter/</guid><description>
Definition Simply put, a Bloom filter is a space-efficient probabilistic data structure with which we can determine the probable existence of a certain thing in a certain data set, and we can determine the non-existence of a certain thing in a certain data set with utmost accuracy. Doing all this in a memory space efficient manner.
In a gist, Bloom filters are about determining if an element may be in a set or is definitely not in a set</description></item><item><title>Keeping up with Upstream Git Repo</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/git-upstream-origin-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/git-upstream-origin-fork/</guid><description>
If you have forked a repository in GitHub that you want to work on, you do so, make your changes locally and once you are confident that everything works, you issue a pull request to the upstream so that your changes can be reviewed and merged. Here is a small snippet that I use to keep my fork up-to-date with the upstream.
upstream - The original repository from which you fork</description></item><item><title>Lamport's Logical Clock - Ordering Events in a Distributed System</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/engineering/lamport-logical-clock-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/engineering/lamport-logical-clock-1/</guid><description>
Basically a distributed system is one in which the components or processes or nodes that comprise a system is distributed across nodes or sometimes even across geographies. But these systems need to communicate with each other to accomplish something meaningful. The most efficient, scalable and proven way of making these distributed systems communicate is via passing messages, sometimes even having a messaging middleware (like Kafka for example.,) as a central component.</description></item><item><title>Deeply disappointed with Travis CI and the way OSS is treated</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/travis-ci-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/travis-ci-1/</guid><description>
I have been a happy user of the Travis CI free usage over the last couple of years. But one announcement recently made me deeply worried. Have a look here at their announcement
Yes, Travis CI will no longer be free for OSS projects. There is no point in blaming Travis CI for this but rather on those idiots who abused the free usage with crypto minites and tor nodes. These bastards completely broke the trust Travis CI free tier gave for OSS projects.</description></item><item><title>CI for Kubernetes Resources</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-deployment-ci/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-deployment-ci/</guid><description>
Recently I have been exploring more around the Kubernetes tooling, especially the ones that can do some pre-validation on the schema and the state of my Kubernetes deployment resources or more precisely the YAML files.
I came across a few of them like conftest, kubeval etc and a wrapper around such set of tools like the kube-tools project which can be used as a GitHub Actions in your GitHub project.</description></item><item><title>GitOps with K8s</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-git-ops-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-git-ops-1/</guid><description>
Some time around the summer of 2019, I came across a blog post where I read about GitOps and I was flattened by the idea itself and ever since I wanted to give it a try on some serious projects but never had the chance to do it professionally. I had a chat about this with many of my colleagues at work and my team, they seemed ro like the idea but were a bit reluctant to employ this concept in their projects.</description></item><item><title>CCTV Monitor with Raspberry Pi &amp; OpenCV</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/raspi-with-opencv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/mlandai/raspi-with-opencv/</guid><description>
I wanted to play around with OpenCV and thought it might be a good idea to try OpenCV with a real life use case. DIY'ing a home camera system that can do motion detection and click images when there is some movement in the frame sounded like a cool idea. So I researched on how I could get this set up done.
There were quite a few things that I should decide, like for example.</description></item><item><title>K8s Cluster SetUp on a Set of Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-raspi-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-raspi-cluster/</guid><description>
Some time ago I managed to set up a 4 node K8s cluster on a set of Raspberry Pi's that were lying idle at my home. In case it interests you, please have a look here for the complete setup, the required components and on how to get it up and running</description></item><item><title>Basics on Blockchain Mining</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/crypto/blockchain-documentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/crypto/blockchain-documentation/</guid><description>
blockchain-documentation This is a summary of the concepts around Blockchain technology!
There are two types of Software architectures exists - Centralized &amp;amp; Distributed A Hybrid architecture is also possible Centrally Distributed architectures Blockchain simply put is a tool to maintain Trust &amp;amp; Integrity in a peer-to-peer system The challenge is to solve the Trust &amp;amp; Integrity in the worst of all situations The Blockchain challenge - The idea behind Mining or Proof-Of-Work: Here is a very simplistic view of what the actual miners do when mining for the Bitcoin, or rather to put it in mathematical terms, solving a puzzle - The puzzle is always to find the leading zeros in the resulting hash of a new block.</description></item></channel></rss>