<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>k8s on bigelectrons</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/tags/k8s/</link><description>Recent content in k8s on bigelectrons</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2018 - 2022 @ https://github.com/Joesan</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bigelectrons.com/tags/k8s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CI for Kubernetes Resources</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-deployment-ci/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-deployment-ci/</guid><description>
Recently I have been exploring more around the Kubernetes tooling, especially the ones that can do some pre-validation on the schema and the state of my Kubernetes deployment resources or more precisely the YAML files.
I came across a few of them like conftest, kubeval etc and a wrapper around such set of tools like the kube-tools project which can be used as a GitHub Actions in your GitHub project.</description></item><item><title>GitOps with K8s</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-git-ops-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-git-ops-1/</guid><description>
Some time around the summer of 2019, I came across a blog post where I read about GitOps and I was flattened by the idea itself and ever since I wanted to give it a try on some serious projects but never had the chance to do it professionally. I had a chat about this with many of my colleagues at work and my team, they seemed ro like the idea but were a bit reluctant to employ this concept in their projects.</description></item><item><title>K8s Cluster SetUp on a Set of Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-raspi-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bigelectrons.com/post/infra/k8s-raspi-cluster/</guid><description>
Some time ago I managed to set up a 4 node K8s cluster on a set of Raspberry Pi's that were lying idle at my home. In case it interests you, please have a look here for the complete setup, the required components and on how to get it up and running</description></item></channel></rss>